Finding Aid for David E. Davis papers
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
David E. Davis papers 1960-2009
Davis, David E., 1930-2011.
2013007 Aa 2
Automotive enthusiast writer who edited Car and Driver and founded Automobile Magazine. Also worked for advertising agencies and served as an industry consultant. Material include correspondence, business files, text of speeches, publicity items, photographs, bound issues of Automobile Magazine and audio-visual material.
21 linear feet in 22 boxes including 1 oversize box
6 film reels 16 mm and 35 mm
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Jeanne Davis (Donor no. 10816) August 2012.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The collection is open without restriction.
David E. Davis, Jr. changed the nature of automotive journalism with his role as the editor of Car and Driver and Automobile Magazine. When he collected some of his writing into a book, it was subtitled, "The collected wit and wisdom of the most influential automotive journalist of our time" (Thus Spake David E. Troy, MI: Momentum Books, 1999).
Born in 1930 Davis became interested in cars as a young boy. After graduating from high school, he went to college but soon dropped out. He worked several different jobs, including a car salesman, and started racing sports cars in 1953. In 1955 however, he crashed during a race and suffered serious injuries to the left side of his face. After recovery and reconstructive surgery, he became involved in writing about rather than racing cars. He worked in advertising management for Road & Track from 1957 to 1960 when he was fired. He soon got a job working for the marketing agency Campbell-Ewald on their Corvette account.
In 1962 Davis left Campbell-Ewald for a position at Car and Driver. He served as editor and then publisher of the magazine until the backlash over a review he wrote of the BMW 2002 led to his resignation in 1967.
After leaving Car and Driver, Davis went back to Campbell-Ewald. In 1969 he was named Senior Vice-President and in 1971 Executive Vice President. In 1976 he returned to Car and Driver as the editor and publisher. He remained at Car and Driver for almost nine years until CBS acquired it from Ziff-Davis Publishing. Davis resigned from Car and Driver in 1985 over disagreements with CBS leadership decisions.
Shortly after resigning, Davis founded a new publication Automobile Magazine, with a capital investment from Rupert Murdoch. The magazine was launched in 1986 and Davis led the magazine until the year 2000.
He continued to be involved in writing, however, for Automobile Magazine, Car and Driver and other publications. In 2006 he became the Editor-in-chief of Winding Road, a new digital online automotive magazine. Throughout his career, he also gave speeches to groups ranging from industry leaders to sports car club members. In 2004 he delivered the commencement address at the University of Michigan and received an honorary doctorate in humane letters.
David E. Davis died in March 2011.
The David E. Davis Papers document various aspects of Davis's work and personal life. The materials have been divided into fifteen series: Personal and Biographical, Correspondence, Business files, Writing, Speeches, Events, Awards, Publicity, Collected materials, Topical files/Miscellaneous, Visual and Audio materials, Removable Storage Media, Oversized materials, Bound Magazines, and Film. With a few exceptions, folder contents reflect original order. Similar documents may be in different folders.
Subjects:
Davis, David E., 1930-2011.; Campbell-Ewald Company.; Advertising--Automobiles--United States.; Antique and classic cars.; Automobile magazine.; Automobile racing.; Automobiles--Marketing.; Automotive journalists--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Car and Driver.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Davis, David E., 1930-2011.; Fangio, Juan Manuel, 1911-1995; Advertising--Automobiles.; Antique and classic cars.; Automobile racing.; Automobiles.; Automobiles--Marketing.
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Davis, David E., 1930-2011.; Spectorsky, A. C. (Auguste C.), 1910-1972.; Automobiles.; Periodicals--Publishing--United States.
Genre Terms:
Advertising.; Commercials.; Compact disks.; Interviews.; Negatives (photographic); Paintings.; Photographs.; Slides (photographs); Sound recordings.
- Personal and biographical 1977-2004
  The Personal and Biographical series contains biographical overviews of Davis's life as well as miscellaneous personal materials. It is arranged alphabetically by description.
  - Biographical information and clippings 1997-2004, undated, 3 folders (Box 1)
    (see also Oversized materials series and Publicity series for biographical articles)
  - Correspondence related to Ann Arbor house and neighborhood 1978, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Personal, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Publicity/promotion: Biographical profile for Corvette News 1965 (Box 1)
- Correspondence 1969-2007
  The Correspondence series consists of letters and memoranda both written and received by David E. Davis. Much of the correspondence relates to his work at Car and Driver and Automobile Magazine, although some is of a more personal nature. This series has been divided into several subseries based on organizational method and the dominant type of correspondence for each grouping. Letters and memoranda are also found in other series of the collection.
  - Outgoing by year 1978-1999
    - Letters and interoffice correspondence from David E. Davis, Jr.
      (1980-1989 correspondence originally arranged in two-pocket folders by year)
      - 1978-1979
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1980
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1981
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1982
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1983
        - Letters (Box 1)
      - 1984
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1985
        - Letters (Box 1)
        - Memos (Box 1)
      - 1986
        - Letters (Box 1)
      - 1987
        - Letters (Box 1)
    - David E. Davis correspondence
      (originally in five binders)
      - December 1987 (Box 1)
      - 1988, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - 1989, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1991, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1992, 4 folders (Box 1)
      - 1993, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1994, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1995, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1996, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - 1998 (Box 2)
      - 1999, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Incoming by Year 1969-2007
    - 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - 1971-1976, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - 1978, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2)
    - 1989 (Box 2)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 2)
    - 2004-2007 (Box 2)
    - Mixed dates, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Incoming by correspondent
    - Mixed correspondents
      - A-R, 15 folders (Box 2)
      - S-Z, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Specific correspondents
      - Devine, Pat (Box 3)
      - Duntov, Zora Arkus (Box 3)
      - Fox, Charles (Box 3)
      - Given, Kyle (Box 3)
      - Gregory, Fred (Box 3)
      - Interpublic Group of Companies (Box 3)
      - Manney, Henry (Box 3)
      - McCall, Bruce (Box 3)
      - Neale, Bill, 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Ramsey, Jim (Box 3)
      - Ruger, Bill (Box 3)
      - Schirmer, Robert H. (Box 3)
      - Voelker, Charlotte (Box 3)
      - Winchell, Frank, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Mixed incoming and outgoing by correspondent
    - Bernard, Hank (Box 3)
    - McCall, Bruce, 4 folders (Box 3)
    - Roettinger, Phil, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Yates, Brock (Box 3)
  - Mixed incoming and outgoing by topic
    - Birthday (Box 3)
    - Death of father 1978 (Box 3)
    - Denon 1994 (Box 3)
    - Desert Island Discs (Box 3)
    - Free Press "Detroit Magazine" (Box 3)
    - Personal, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - St. David's Day (Box 3)
    - Steyr-Daimler-Puch Dr. techn. E GONE RUDOLF (Box 3)
- Business files 1961-2008
  The Business files series contains materials regarding Davis's work at the marketing agencies Campbell-Ewald and Foote, Cone & Belding, the magazines Car and Driver and Automobile Magazine, and other organizations. The material is grouped chronologically into subseries by organization. Within the subseries, materials are arranged alphabetically by topic and then chronologically. When Davis worked for an organization (Campbell-Ewald and Car and Driver) over multiple, distinct periods of time, multiple subseries have been created to reflect that. The types of material included in these subseries vary widely, from paper copies of presentations slides, to fan letters, to survey research statistics. In addition, more material related to Davis's work at these organizations may be found throughout the collection.
  - Campbell-Ewald
    (employed 1960-1962)
    - Advertisements (Box 4)
      - Corvair ads 1961-1962 (Box 4)
      - Corvette ads 1960-1962 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous ads 1960-1962 (Box 4)
    - Mixed Materials
      - Memoranda and "ideas," 1954-1961, undated (Box 4)
      - Memoranda and writing, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Car and Driver
    (employed 1962-1967)
    - Memoranda 1962-1967 (Box 4)
    - Publicity/promotion: Speeches
      - Renault Dealers circa September 1964 (Box 4)
      - Philadelphia SCCA February 1965 (Box 4)
      - Volkswagen dealers July 17, 1965 (Box 4)
      - N.Y. Auto Fraternity circa September 1965 (Box 4)
      - Rochester SCCA December 4, 1965 (Box 4)
      - Fort Wayne SCCA December 10, 1965 (Box 4)
      - Henry Ford Museum January 14, 1966 (Box 4)
        (also includes other miscellaneous speeches)
      - N,E. Ohio SCCA, February 12,1966 (Box 4)
    - Publicity/promotion: Television and Radio
      - "Barry Farber" Show April 22, 1964 (Box 4)
        (see also Visual and audio materials series, under Audio tapes)
      - "Open Mind" Show April 4, 1965 (Box 4)
      - Ralph Nader debate March 1, 1966 (Box 4)
      - Corvair commercial 1966 (Box 4)
    - Publicity/promotion: Writing
      - Automobile Quarterly 1964 (Box 4)
      - TV Guide 1965 (Box 4)
      - American Youth Magazine 1966 (Box 4)
      - "Grand Prix," 1966 (Box 4)
      - "Swan Song" editorial 1966 (Box 4)
      - "Swan Song" letters 1966-1967 (Box 4)
      - Racing Annual 1967 (Box 4)
  - Campbell-Ewald
    (employed 1967-1976)
    - Five-year planning 1969-1970, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Memoranda and mixed materials 1968-1975, 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous editorials 1969-1976, 2 folders (Box 4)
    - National Council of Corvette Clubs 1970 (Box 4)
    - Report: "Advertising not Placed is Non-commissionable," 1974 (Box 4)
    - Speeches and presentations
      - Michigan Advertising Round Table September 24, 1970 (Box 4)
      - Creative workshop: Ad age 1972, 1973 (Box 4)
      - National Glass Dealer Association March 9, 1973 (Box 4)
  - Car and Driver
    (employed 1976-1985)
    - Ann Arbor 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - Buyer's guide 1978-1980 (Box 4)
    - Challenge V 1976 (Box 4)
    - Complimentary copies 1978 (Box 4)
    - Consultants 1977 (Box 4)
    - Detroit trip 1976 (Box 5)
    - Goodbye letters from fans 1985 (Box 5)
    - Henry Ford Museum 1978 (Box 5)
    - Interoffice communication ("New York files") 1975-1978, 4 folders (Box 5)
    - Magazine covers
      - 1971-1973 (Box 5)
      - 1973-1975 (Box 5)
      - 1976 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous circa 1978 (Box 5)
    - Mr. Toad 1976-1977 (Box 5)
    - Nemacolin meeting 1977 (Box 5)
    - Offer letter 1975 (Box 5)
    - Research reports
      - 1975 (Box 5)
      - 1977 (Box 5)
      - 1981-1982 (Box 5)
    - Story ideas undated (Box 5)
    - Test cars
      - GMC Suburban 1984 (Box 5)
      - Long term test cars 1977 (Box 5)
      - Mercedes-Benz Turbowagen project 1980-1984 (Box 5)
      - Pontiac Trans-Am 1982 (Box 5)
      - Porsche 944 1983-1984 (Box 5)
      - Volvo "Boss Wagon 1977-1979 (Box 5)
      - Volvo wagon 1985 (Box 5)
  - Automobile Magazine
    (employed 1985-2000)
    - Advertising/ media proposals and information
      - Business week promotion 1987-1988 (Box 5)
      - In-house advertising memos, letters, etc. 1989-1997 (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous proposals and information 1991-1993, 2 folders (Box 5)
      - Marketing file 1997-1998 (Box 5)
      - Primedia 1998-1999 (Box 5)
    - All-Stars 1998 (Box 5)
    - Articles 2003 (Box 5)
    - C10 pickup 1995-1997 (Box 5)
    - Corporate materials (Murdoch Magazines, K-III Magazines)
      - Murdoch magazine material circa 1985 (Box 5)
      - News America Publishing 1986-1990 (Box 5)
      - Murdoch memos and correspondence 1986-1991 (Box 5)
      - K-III/Bill Reilly information (clippings) 1991 (Box 5)
      - Letters from corporate (K-III) 1991-1997 (Box 5)
      - Reprint of article about K-III in Folio, 1993 (Box 5)
      - K-III Acquisition candidate: McMullen & Lee 1994-1995 (Box 5)
      - Memos from K-III magazine 1994-1996 (Box 5)
      - KIII Press releases 1994-1997 (Box 5)
    - Expense Reports
      - 1988-1997, 9 folders (Box 6)
      - circa 1999, 2 folders (Box 6)
        (originally labeled "Old Expense Reports)
      - "Current expenses," 1999 (Box 6)
        (includes an envelope labeled "Questionable DED Expenses 1999")
      - Unreimbursed expenses 2000 (Box 6)
    - Memoranda 1985-1991 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous proposals
      - Adaptation of an unfinished play 1988 (Box 6)
      - Dial-a-Book 1994 (Box 6)
      - Mixed undated, 1993-1996, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Studio 303 1989 (Box 6)
    - Research and statistics
      - Peterson information 1996 (Box 6)
      - Subscriber studies 1989-1990 (Box 6)
      - Subscriber survey 1987, 3 folders (Box 6)
    - 60 second script 1997 (Box 6)
    - Sponsored events
      - Auto expo 1986, 1987 (Box 6)
      - CART info 1998 (Box 6)
      - European Grand Tour (Box 7)
        - Mixed materials 1991 (Box 7)
          (originally labeled "Travelers' remarks")
        - Mixed materials 1993 (Box 7)
        - Road Book 1994 (Box 7)
      - Perfect 10 Celebration Tour 1996 (Box 7)
      - Saab Ride-and-Drive, 28 October 1998 (Box 7)
  - Winding Road Magazine
    (2006-)
    - CNBC "Behind the Wheel," 2006 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous 2005-2007 (Box 7)
  - Foote, Cone & Belding (FCB)/Interpublic Group (IPG)
    - 2001 (Box 7)
    - 2002, 6 folders (Box 7)
    - 2003, 2 folders (Box 7)
    - 2004, 10 folders (Box 7)
    - 2005, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Leo-Arthur Kelmenson & Associates (LAK) (Box 8)
    - 2008 undated (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous consulting work
    - The Davis Group Incorporated
      - Correspondence and financial information 1967-1969 (Box 8)
      - Publicity/Promotion
        - Gurney Eagle Memberships 1968 (Box 8)
        - Los Angeles Times 1965-1968 (Box 8)
          (originally labeled as being from 1966)
        - Los Angeles Times 1967-1968 (Box 8)
          (originally labeled as being from 1967)
        - Speech to BSA Dealers January 19, 1968 (Box 8)
    - MacManus, John & Adams 1965, undated (Box 8)
    - Freeman & Gossage, Inc. 1964, undated (Box 8)
- Writing 1963-2000
  The Writing series contains materials related to some of Davis's writing including texts of articles, background material, and correspondence related to the articles. The series is arranged alphabetically by topic or article title.
  - "Bill Neale: Good Friend, nice guy, great talent." AFAS July 1991 (Box 8)
  - "Breakfast with Stirling," undated (Box 8)
  - Civil disobedience 1977 (Box 8)
  - Consumers Union 1978 (Box 8)
  - "Drivers Seat" column history/lists of articles 1963-1990 (Box 8)
  - Dune Buggies 1967 (Box 8)
  - Electric car (GM Impact) circa 1990 (Box 8)
  - "Everything Old is New Again" story for Forbes FYI circa 1990 (Box 8)
  - General Electric article (titled "Another View, from Ann Arbor") 1990 (Box 8)
  - Giugiaro Catalogue Raisonne August 26, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Henry Ford Museum (piece on Bill Mitchell) undated (Box 8)
  - Interview with himself 1998 (Box 8)
  - Jaguar SS 100 undated (Box 8)
  - "Jesus Christ and the Boy Scouts Meet Personal Responsibility: The Role of the Gentleman between now and the Year 2000" 1972 (Box 8)
  - "Just imagine..." article for Russo Ferrari 1990 (Box 8)
  - "Lime Rock," undated (Box 8)
  - "Love and the Automobile," undated (Box 8)
  - Magazine research circa 1970, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Mercedes-Benz SSK undated (Box 8)
  - Mixed
    - Articles & Quotes in other publications 1962-2000, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - General 1997, undated, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - "Packard Station Wagon," undated (Box 8)
  - "Paradise Lost: Decline of the Auto-industrial Age," undated (Box 8)
  - Sample scripts undated (Box 8)
  - "Sports Car Mystique," undated (Box 8)
  - "Used cars," undated (Box 8)
  - Reporter's notebooks, 12 items (Box 8)
- Speeches 1968-2009
  The Speeches series consists of the text and correspondence for speeches Davis delivered to a wide variety of groups and organizations. The speeches have been arranged chronologically and grouped into 5-year subseries to make the list easier to read. Many of the speeches contain anecdotes from Davis's life as well as his perspective on various topics and issues.
  - 1968-1973
    - BSA Eastern Dealers' Convention January 19, 1968 (Box 8)
    - AMA [American Marketing Association?], Miami October 27, 1970 (Box 8)
    - National Glass Dealers Association, Atlanta, GA March 9, 1973 (Box 8)
    - Adcraft luncheon April 6, 1973 (Box 8)
  - 1975-1979
    - Toledo AAF September 26, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Introduction of T. B. Adams, Campbell-Ewald International, Dusseldorf, Germany May 18, 1976 (Box 8)
    - CeCo speech April 27, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Creative Seminar 3 speech, Tampa, FL October 14, 1977 (Box 8)
    - Editorial presentation circa 1977 (Box 8)
    - Creative Seminar 3 speech, Aspen, CO July 29, 1978 (Box 8)
    - GMI speech October 18, 1979 (Box 8)
  - 1980-1984
    - Nissan speech circa 1980 (Box 8)
    - Unknown audience circa 1980 (Box 8)
    - Porsche-Audi Dealers speech May 15, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Koni Distributors Convention speech September 11, 1980 (Box 8)
    - Worldwide Volkswagen convention, Scottsdale, AZ February 28, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Kiwanis speech May 4, 1981 (Box 8)
    - SEMA speech June 7, 1981 (Box 8)
    - National Tire Wholesalers July 30, 1981 (Box 8)
    - Alfa-Romeo Convention, Detroit August 1, 1981 (Box 8)
    - GMI speech January 19, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Ashland Chemical speech August 25, 1982 (Box 8)
    - Volkswagen speech September 29, 1982 (Box 8)
    - GM Sales and Marketing Conference November 8, 1982 (Box 8)
    - SCCA speech January 15, 1983 (Box 9)
    - General Motors Conference April 5, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Porshe-Audi Dealers May 10, 1983 (Box 9)
    - B.F. Goodrich speech June 6, 1983 (Box 9)
    - SAE Toastmaster notes June 23, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Beaver speech December 8, 1983 (Box 9)
    - Goodrich speech and related Art Spinella material circa 1984 (Box 9)
    - Ford Motor Company (Merchanding) February 15, 1984 (Box 9)
    - SEMA speech May 4, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Z/D Single Copy Sales meeting May 31, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Volkswagen Management speech June 6, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Ford Engineering speech June 20, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Indian Head speech June 21, 1984 (Box 9)
    - General Motors (B-O-C and C-P-C groups) September 13, 1984 (Box 9)
    - Volkswagen speech, San Diego October 1984 (Box 9)
    - Lincoln-Mercury Merkur video tape script, October 1984 (Box 9)
      (date from original folder label)
    - Lincoln-Mercury Dealers speech October 23, 1984 (Box 9)
  - 1985-1989
    - Lincoln-Mercury Dealers, Philadelphia January 31, 1985 (Box 9)
    - CBS Sales Conference/Amelia Island April 11, 1985 (Box 9)
    - CBS Editorial College and Central Michigan April 17, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Chevrolet Management speech April 29, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Driver Education Association May 3, 1985 (Box 9)
    - CBS Sales meeting May 14, 1985 (Box 9)
    - National Parking Association May 22, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Chrysler-Plymouth AAA Troubleshooting Contest June 17, 1985 (Box 9)
    - GM Master Technician Program July 11, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Ford Dealer Advertising Conference July 25, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Ford Dealer Advertising Conference December 4, 1985 (Box 9)
    - Dow Corning Auto Tech seminar December 5, 1985 (Box 9)
    - IMPA speech January 23, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Preston Mann Roast speech April 17, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Ford Talk, Renaissance Center April 29, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Maritz-Consumer video disc recording May 5, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Select Sales Conference May 11, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Detroit Country Day School commencement speech June 11, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Aspen Board Meeting, Aspen, CO June 21, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Corvette Speech, Williamsburg July 7, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Toyota Management Luncheon, Los Angeles July 17, 1986 (Box 9)
    - U[niversity?] of M[ichigan?] Management seminar August 1986 (Box 9)
    - Ford Executive Development Program, Renaissance Center, Detroit September 16, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Brad Briggs's Retirement Roast September 25, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Volkswagen speech, Orlando November 11, 1986 (Box 9)
    - Chrysler Corp Management Club, Troy, MI November 12, 1986 (Box 9)
      (missing first page)
    - IAA speech February 17, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Madison Avenue Sports Car and Chowder Society March 10, 1987 (Box 9)
    - University of Michigan SAE (Society of Automotive Engineers) March 26, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Toyota Board of Governor's Meeting, San Diego, CA April 9, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Mercedes-Benz Startech, Denver, CO April 11, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Adcraft PM meeting April 15, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Michigan Journalism Fellows April 21, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Tennessee Automotive Manufacturers Association. (TAMA) June 18, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Ford SAE video presentation August 31, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Prince Corporation Strategic Planning Session October 15, 1987 (Box 9)
    - D'Arcy, Masius, Benton, and Bowles October 2, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Pontiac Motor Division "Image" speech December 7, 1987 (Box 9)
    - Adcraft Club March 11, 1988 (Box 9)
    - U[niversity?] of M[ichigan?] Psychology Career Class April 6, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Tom Staudt Retirement speech April 28, 1988 (Box 9)
    - U[niversity?] of M[ichigan?] Automotive Symposium September 16, 1988 (Box 9)
    - Jim Fuller Eulogy January 5, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Mercedes-Benz, Tucson, AZ January 19, 1989 (Box 9)
    - UCLA speech February 21, 1989 (Box 9)
    - GE Management March 1, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Los Angeles Ad Club April 19, 1989 (Box 9)
    - SEMA Conference May 12, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Walter Hayes Retirement May 16, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Lincoln-Mercury, Naples, FL June 9, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Honda Dealers meeting June 22, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Mercedes-Benz Gullwing speech, Dearborn, MI September 23, 1989 (Box 9)
    - D.R.I./McGraw-Hill, Dearborn, MI October 10, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Tri-State Cadillac Dealers, New York City October 24, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Mercedes-Benz Dealer meeting, Atlantic City, NJ October 24, 1989 (Box 9)
    - Pontiac Masters meeting, Hawaii November 1989 (Box 9)
  - 1990-1994
    - BMW Club, Rochester, NY January 27, 1990 (Box 9)
    - AJAC, Toronto February 15, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Honda speech, Torrence, CA March 5, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Ford Dealers speech, Detroit, MI March 7, 1990 (Box 9)
    - SCCA, Detroit Region, speech, Livonia, MI April 17, 1990 (Box 9)
    - NAFA (National Association of Fleet Administrators) speech, Houston, TX April 25, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Shelby Owners speech July 7, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Chrysler Key Supplier speech, Milford, MI August 22, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Lexus Speech, Chicago, Atlanta, New York, and Newport Beach September 1990 (Box 9)
    - Ogilvy and Mather, Autotrends Panel, Dearborn, MI November 1, 1990 (Box 9)
    - Amoco speech, Chicago, IL December 7, 1990 (Box 9)
    - "America is trying to tell us something...," circa 1990 (Box 9)